<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Mapping the Gay Guides</title>
    <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Mapping the Gay Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#39;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/by.svg&#39; height=&#39;25&#39;&gt; Licensed CC-BY.&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Launch of Mapping the Gay Guides!</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/2020/02/announcing-the-launch-of-mapping-the-gay-guides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/2020/02/announcing-the-launch-of-mapping-the-gay-guides/</guid>
      <description>Today we’re excited to officially launch the first phase of Mapping the Gay Guides.
What is Mapping the Gay Guides?   Mapping the Gay Guides (MGG) is a digital mapping project that aims to understand often ignored queer geographies using the Damron Address Books, an early but longstanding travel guide aimed at gay men since the early 1960s. Similar in function to the green books used by African Americans during the Jim Crow era to help identity businesses that catered to black clients in the South, the Damron Guides aided a generation of queer people to identity sites of community, pleasure, and politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric Gonzaba</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/gonzaba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/gonzaba/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Eric Gonzaba is an Assistant Professor of American Studies at California State University, Fullerton. He received his doctorate in American History from George Mason University in 2019. A specialist in African American history and LGBT culture, he’s currently completing a book on the culture and politics of gay nightlife in Washington, D.C., Baltimore, and Philadelphia since 1970.
Beyond his research, Gonzaba strives to find innovative ways to teach and understand our past, especially through digital public history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Gay Guides</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/map/</guid>
      <description>This map may take a moment to load.   iframe { min-width: 100%; } 
  iFrameResize({ heightCalculationMethod: &#39;taggedElement&#39; });  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methodology</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/methodology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/methodology/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Dataset Turning a historical document, such as the Damron Address Books, into data that can be used for mapping is a process fraught with methodological decisions that shape the resulting dataset. The goal of this page is to make visible the choices that were made and clarify our categorization of data.
 Figure 1. Example of typical listings in the Damron Address Book.
  Although the Damron Guides have been digitized up until 1980 they are only available via an academic subscription to the Alexander Street LGBT Thought and Culture database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Statement on Ethics</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/ethics/</guid>
      <description>Digital historians have ethical obligations, especially when they work with materials and subject matters that relate to marginalized communities. Since this project is centered on the culture of gay, lesbian, bisexual, transgender, and queer people, the Mapping the Gay Guides team strives to make our project ethically responsible, respecting the privacy, perspectives, and dignity of those whose stories are reflected within our work.
The data in Mapping the Gay Guides reflects thousands of sites important to development of queer (mostly gay male) culture since the 1960s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southern Black Queer Spaces</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/southern-black-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/southern-black-spaces/</guid>
      <description>iframe { min-width: 50%; }    Figure 1. This map shows the number of locations listed in the Damron Guides and categorized as (B) for each year from 1965 to 1980. Use the slider to change the year or hit the play button to animate the map. Click here for a more expansive map exploring the LGBTQ past since 1965.
    iFrameResize({ heightCalculationMethod: &#39;taggedElement&#39; });  With our data from U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this Project</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the Gay Guides aims to understand often ignored queer geographies using the Damron Address Books, an early but longstanding travel guide aimed at gay men since the early 1960s. Similar in function to the green books used by African Americans during the Jim Crow era to help identity businesses that catered to black clients in the South, the Damron Guides aided a generation of queer people to identity sites of community, pleasure, and politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amanda Regan</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/regan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/regan/</guid>
      <description>Amanda Regan is a historian of the late-nineteenth and twentieth-centuries and is currently a Digital Humanities Postdoctoral Fellow at Southern Methodist University’s Center for Presidential History. She earned her PhD in History from George Mason University in 2019.
Her research sits at the intersection of women’s history, fitness history, and history of the body and her work often relies upon computational methodologies as a research tool for examining large corpuses of primary sources and gleaning new insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Alabama have an LGBTQ history?</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/alabama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/alabama/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1. From Martinac’s The Queerest Places. Despite her excellent coverage of the American South, no Alabama sites are listed.
  Does Alabama have an LGBTQ history? In her 1997 travel guide The Queerest Places: A Guide to Gay and Lesbian Historic Sites, Paula Martinac provides readers wonderful descriptions of historical places of interest related to queer history. She divides her summaries by states from five regions: New England, the Mid-Atlantic, the Midwest, the West, and the South.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization: Mapping the Alabama Gay Guides</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/maps/alabama/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/maps/alabama/</guid>
      <description>  iframe { min-width: 100%; }    iFrameResize({ heightCalculationMethod: &#39;taggedElement&#39; });  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborators</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/interns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/interns/</guid>
      <description>California State University Fullerton Graduate Research Assistants, Spring 2020 
Christian Castillo Christian is a MA student in the Department of American Studies at California State University, Fullerton. They are interested in queer studies, gender and sex.   Laura Fauvor Laura Fauvor is currently a M.A. student of the American Studies at California State University, Fullerton. She received her B.A. in History and American Studies from California State University, Long Beach and her A.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>