<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>case-study on Mapping the Gay Guides</title>
    <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/tags/case-study/</link>
    <description>Recent content in case-study on Mapping the Gay Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#39;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/by.svg&#39; height=&#39;25&#39;&gt; Licensed CC-BY.&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/tags/case-study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(PT) is for Pool Table</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/pt-is-for-pool-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/pt-is-for-pool-table/</guid>
      <description>Whether you’re new to using Mapping the Gay Guides or not, you’ll know that one of the most helpful ways to explore our dataset is using what we call “amenity features.” These amenity features can be found in the original Damron Address Books and were a letter coding system that helped the reader know a little bit more about a listed establishment. For example, a popular site (say, a busy bar) would often have a star next to the bar’s name (in place of a star, our team at Mapping the Gay Guides uses an asterisk *).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hotel in Bohemia</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/a-hotel-in-bohemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/a-hotel-in-bohemia/</guid>
      <description>So many of the entries in Bob Damron Address Books appear unremarkable. (I mean, not all bars can have a history like Stonewall, right?) The vast majority of listings in the gay guides don’t provide much context or historical information, and so it requires historians and the wider public to give meaning to these lists of addresses. But even if wider context doesn’t always lead to cinematic stories of police raids or resistance, it doesn’t mean we can’t learn more about queer life in America through these guides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policing Balboa Park</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/policing-balboa-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/policing-balboa-park/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1. Cabrillo Bridge in Balboa Park, 1980. Los Angeles Times May 15, 1980, SD A1.
  In a 1971 article of Queen’s Quarterly, a magazine for “Gay Guys Who Have No Hangups,” San Diego was promoted as the city with “Something for Everyone.”1 For those curious readers, San Diego was promised as a city with little to no harassment for gay men, especially in comparison to the brutal homophobic treatment by police in neighboring Los Angeles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The History of Club Ripples</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/club-ripples/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/club-ripples/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1. Club Ripples. Photo courtesy of Jen Zepeda.
  At some point during the summer of 2017, I recall that my friends and I wandered into Ripples after leaving Panama Joe’s on Second St in Long Beach, CA. I remember searching for the nearest gay club on Google Maps and being surprised that there was one less than half a mile away, facing the beach. As we turned the corner onto Ocean Boulevard, we looked up at the six flags that sat on top of the club which, together, made a rainbow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Closer at Lesbian Spaces in the Bay Area</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/looking-closer-lesbian-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/looking-closer-lesbian-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1. The Paper Doll. Photo compliment of the GLBT Historical Society via the Gale Archives of Sexuality and Gender.
  While entering the data for Damron’s listings, we couldn’t help but notice the fleeting nature of queer spaces; many entries would be listed one year and gone the next. We also couldn’t help but notice a lack of queer spaces for women. Damron’s guide primarily caters to white gay males while occasionally noting some spaces for queer women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paramount Steak House: A Forever Listing</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/parmount-steakhouse-a-forever-listing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/parmount-steakhouse-a-forever-listing/</guid>
      <description>One of the reasons why our team loves this project is because the site helps us understand the queer culture through spaces that no longer make up the modern United States. That is, the vast majority of the listings you’ll see in the Damron Address Books and in our data are spaces that are no longer in operation. Queer businesses, just like non-queer commercial spaces, come and go with the economic times, and thus the bars, baths, theaters, bookstores, restaurants, and other shops located within our data are largely historical records, no longer representing sites still in operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Listing Tragically Disappears: The Upstairs Lounge Fire in New Orleans</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/a-listing-disappears/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/a-listing-disappears/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1. Postcard of Pontchartrain Beach amusement park, New Orleans, a popular site for African American cruising according to the Damron guides. Source: Wikimedia Commons
  This past week, millions around the world celebrated Mardi Gras, a lively and colorful celebration before the fasting season of Lent. In the United States, the celebration is most closely associated with the parish of New Orleans, the largest municipality in Louisiana. Each year, hundreds of thousands of tourists descend on the Crescent City to enjoy the city’s infectious Dixieland jazz, flavorful cuisine, and of course its storied and often tragic history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southern Black Queer Spaces</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/southern-black-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/articles/southern-black-spaces/</guid>
      <description>iframe { min-width: 50%; }    Figure 1. This map shows the number of locations listed in the Damron Guides and categorized as (B) for each year from 1965 to 1980. Use the slider to change the year or hit the play button to animate the map. Click here for a more expansive map exploring the LGBTQ past since 1965.
    iFrameResize({ heightCalculationMethod: &#39;taggedElement&#39; });  With our data from U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
