<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Mapping the Gay Guides</title>
    <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Mapping the Gay Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#39;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/by.svg&#39; height=&#39;25&#39;&gt; Licensed CC-BY.&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Out Resistance</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/rivera-sierra-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/rivera-sierra-reflection/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by Sierra Rivera, a MA student in the Department of American Studies at California State University. Fullerton. Over the course of a semester during the Spring of 2020, Rivera was a Graduate Research Assistant on MGG. She transcribed thousands of entries in the 1970s Damron guides. Here, she reflects on the Damron guides as a form of resistance and her experiences working on a digital history project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Year Working on Mapping the Gay Guides</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/bucca-dominick-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/bucca-dominick-reflection/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by Dominick Bucca, a MA student in the Department of History and Geography at Clemson University. Over the course of the 2021-2022 year, Bucca was a Graduate Research Assistant on MGG. He began by transcribing a year of the Damron Guides and then moved to working with unclear entries. Here, he reflects on his experience working on a digital history project and how that influenced his own work in a class on the social history of film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Semester Working on Mapping the Gay Guides</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/dillard-jillian-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/dillard-jillian-reflection/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by Jillian Dillard, a graduating senior at Clemson University. Over the course of the Spring 2022 semester, Jillian worked with Dr. Regan to transcribe and geolocate data for Canadian entries in the Bob Damron Address Books. Here, she reflects on her experience working on a digital history project and shares some of the things she learned while working on the project.
My experience working on Mapping the Gay Guides has been my first in depth experience working on a digital history project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Gay Guides Reviewed in Scholarly Editing</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/review-scholarlyediting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/review-scholarlyediting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Grant to Add Over 116,000 LGBTQ Spaces to Mapping Project</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/national-grant-csuf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/national-grant-csuf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Gay Guides preserves LGBTQ history through online map</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/spectrum-news-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/spectrum-news-one/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic gay travel guides written during less welcoming times to go online</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/gcn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/gcn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Project Is Bringing the Gay ‘Green Book’ Online</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/next-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/next-city/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MGG to expand with support of NEH</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/neh-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/neh-funding/</guid>
      <description>The Mapping the Gay Guides team is pleased to announce that we have received a three-year grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities to support the expansion of Mapping the Gay Guides. This generous support comes from the Humanities Collections and Reference Resources program within the NEH’s Division of Preservation and Access.
This funding will allow us to expand Mapping the Gay Guides in several ways.
First, it will allow the MGG team to digitize and transcribe another twenty years of data from the Bob Damron Address Books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MGG named Honorable Mention for 2020 Garfinkel Prize in Digital Humanities</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/award-garfinkel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/award-garfinkel/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that the directors of Mapping the Gay Guides, Dr. Amanda Regan and Dr. Eric Gonzaba, have been named an honorable mention for the 2020 Garfinkel Prize in the Digital Humanities by the American Studies Association&amp;rsquo;s Digital Humanities Caucus.
The Garfinkel Prize in Digital Humanities is an award that honors caucus founder Susan Garfinkel for her longstanding service to the caucus and her commitment to an inclusive, interdisciplinary, welcoming Digital Humanities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MGG wins 2021 Emerging Open Scholarship Award</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/award-openscholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/award-openscholarship/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that the directors of Mapping the Gay Guides, Dr. Amanda Regan and Dr. Eric Gonzaba, have been awarded the 2021 Emerging Open Scholarship Award by the Canadian Social Knowledge Institute.
The award recognizes open scholarship that incorporates open access, open data, open education, and other related movements that have the potential to make scholarly work more efficient, more accessible, and more usable by those within and beyond the academy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are Everywhere. The Bob Damron Address Books were a lifeline for gay travelers in the 1960s and 70s.</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/slate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/slate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This New Map Is Digitizing LGBTQ&#43; Travel Guides from the &#39;60s and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/condenast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/condenast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Gay Guides Project highlights historic queer spaces</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/ebar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/ebar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Gay Guides project plots queer spaces, launches digital map</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/windy-city-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/windy-city-times/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Voice: Student finds community, pride in project mapping historical gay friendly spots</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/ocregister/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/ocregister/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Queer Space in America Mapping the Gay Guides Project Plots Historical Spaces on a Digital Map</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/vizualizing-queer-space-csuf-newsservice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/vizualizing-queer-space-csuf-newsservice/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Interactive Map Visualizes the Queer Geography of 20th-Century America</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/smithsonian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/smithsonian/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Launch of Mapping the Gay Guides!</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/launch-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/launch-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Today we’re excited to officially launch the first phase of Mapping the Gay Guides.
What is Mapping the Gay Guides? Mapping the Gay Guides (MGG) is a digital mapping project that aims to understand often ignored queer geographies using the Damron Address Books, an early but longstanding travel guide aimed at gay men since the early 1960s. Similar in function to the green books used by African Americans during the Jim Crow era to help identity businesses that catered to black clients in the South, the Damron Guides aided a generation of queer people to identity sites of community, pleasure, and politics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
