<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Mapping the Gay Guides</title>
    <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Mapping the Gay Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#39;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://mirrors.creativecommons.org/presskit/icons/by.svg&#39; height=&#39;25&#39;&gt; Licensed CC-BY.&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MGG to expand with support of NEH</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/neh-funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/neh-funding/</guid>
      <description>The Mapping the Gay Guides team is pleased to announce that we have received a three-year grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities to support the expansion of Mapping the Gay Guides. This generous support comes from the Humanities Collections and Reference Resources program within the NEH’s Division of Preservation and Access.
  This funding will allow us to expand Mapping the Gay Guides in several ways.
First, it will allow the MGG team to digitize and transcribe another twenty years of data from the Bob Damron Address Books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MGG named Honorable Mention for 2020 Garfinkel Prize in Digital Humanities</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/award-garfinkel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/award-garfinkel/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that the directors of Mapping the Gay Guides, Dr. Amanda Regan and Dr. Eric Gonzaba, have been named an honorable mention for the 2020 Garfinkel Prize in the Digital Humanities by the American Studies Association&amp;rsquo;s Digital Humanities Caucus.
  The Garfinkel Prize in Digital Humanities is an award that honors caucus founder Susan Garfinkel for her longstanding service to the caucus and her commitment to an inclusive, interdisciplinary, welcoming Digital Humanities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MGG wins 2021 Emerging Open Scholarship Award</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/award-openscholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/award-openscholarship/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that the directors of Mapping the Gay Guides, Dr. Amanda Regan and Dr. Eric Gonzaba, have been awarded the 2021 Emerging Open Scholarship Award by the Canadian Social Knowledge Institute.
  The award recognizes open scholarship that incorporates open access, open data, open education, and other related movements that have the potential to make scholarly work more efficient, more accessible, and more usable by those within and beyond the academy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are Everywhere. The Bob Damron Address Books were a lifeline for gay travelers in the 1960s and 70s.</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/slate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/slate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This New Map Is Digitizing LGBTQ&#43; Travel Guides from the &#39;60s and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/condenast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/condenast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Gay Guides project plots queer spaces, launches digital map</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/windy-city-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/windy-city-times/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Titan Voice: Student finds community, pride in project mapping historical gay friendly spots</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/ocregister/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/ocregister/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Queer Space in America Mapping the Gay Guides Project Plots Historical Spaces on a Digital Map</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/vizualizing-queer-space-csuf-newsservice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/vizualizing-queer-space-csuf-newsservice/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Interactive Map Visualizes the Queer Geography of 20th-Century America</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/smithsonian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/smithsonian/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Launch of Mapping the Gay Guides!</title>
      <link>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/launch-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mappingthegayguides.org/news/launch-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Today we’re excited to officially launch the first phase of Mapping the Gay Guides.
What is Mapping the Gay Guides?   Mapping the Gay Guides (MGG) is a digital mapping project that aims to understand often ignored queer geographies using the Damron Address Books, an early but longstanding travel guide aimed at gay men since the early 1960s. Similar in function to the green books used by African Americans during the Jim Crow era to help identity businesses that catered to black clients in the South, the Damron Guides aided a generation of queer people to identity sites of community, pleasure, and politics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
